hey what's going on everybody in this
topic I'm going to explain variables and
data types in python as well as give you
a few useful tips and tricks at the end
of this topic so why don't you sit back
relax and enjoy the show
let's talk about variables a variable is
a reusable container for storing a value
a variable behaves as if it were the
value it contains think back to algebra
class back in the day we have an
equation that contains x x is some
representation of a value wherever we
use x it behaves as if it were a certain
number that's kind of the same thing
with programming now when we create a
variable we would like to give a
descriptive and unique name of what that
variable contains suppose I'm working
with a user's Edge I could declare a
variable named age age equals then some
value let's say my age is 21 not anymore
but I like to think it still is guys I'm
getting old I can use this variable age
and it will behave as if it were the
number 21. to print a variable you can
place it within a print statement
print age
my age is 21. if you're printing a
variable you don't need to put it within
quotes
because what we're doing then is
literally printing the word age and not
the variable if you need to display a
variable along with some text such as
you are age years old what we could do
is shrink concatenation wherever you
would like to include a variable let's
say here where ages we can separate this
line of text into different strings you
are
plus age plus the text years old
so we do have an error here type error
can only concatenate string not into
Strings we can't add numbers to Strings
directly we would need to do what is
called typecasting to display a number
along with subtext we would need to cast
this variable which is a number into
text a string to do that we can precede
the variable name with s t r then
surround the variable with a set of
parentheses
if I were to run this again this will
display you are 21 years old but you do
have to pay attention to your spaces I'm
going to add a space after r as well as
before the word years run this again you
are 21 years old another way to display
a variable along with some text is to
separate the text and variables in two
separate arguments
print then write our text within quotes
you
you are
wherever you would like to add a
variable add a comma then the variable
name if you have more text that follows
add another comma
then add some additional text you are
age years old
so what we've done is separated our
strings and variables into different
arguments each separated with a comma
but if you separate your variables and
text into separate arguments you'll
include a space automatically so I'm
going to get rid of the space after R
and before the word ears
so spacing is pretty important depending
on which method you use these two print
statements will output the same thing
you are 21 years old the third way to
print a variable along with some text
and this is becoming the more popular
way of doing things is to use what is
called an F string
print a set of quotes precede your
quotes with f
u r wherever you would like to insert a
variable add a set of curly braces the
curly braces are acting as a placeholder
for a value or variable we will place
our variable age within the curly braces
so yeah those are three different ways
to Output a variable along with some
text as of the filming of this video
fstrings are becoming much more popular
for output for the rest of the series we
will be using fstrings but you should
still be aware of the existence of these
other two methods as well I need to
discuss different data types there's
four basic data types in Python there's
still more but these are four for
beginners we have integers floats
strings and booleans let's begin with
integers
we'll create three integer variables for
example we have age
another whole number could be maybe
players or users you're not going to
have half a player right
or nine tenths of a player it's going to
be a whole number you have one two three
or more players all whole numbers then
maybe quantity maybe somebody is buying
something quantity equals five you
wouldn't have like half a product right
it would be a whole number
then let's display some of these
variables
print we'll use fstrings because we like
fstrings
you
are
age years old this is the same from the
previous example
let's use players
there are
players
than the word players
online
then quantity let's use this
you would like to buy
our variable quantity
items
let's run this
you are 21 years old there are two
players online you would like to buy
five items
so those are integers they're just whole
numbers
I'm going to turn these lines into
comments and then we can continue
let's move on to floats
a float is a number that contains a
decimal portion for example maybe a GPA
that's usually a decimal
my GPA is 3.2
what about a distance this could be
kilometers miles whatever
2.5 kilometers
um price price could be afloat price
equals 10.99
let's display some of these
let's print our GPA
your GPA is
GPA
let's print distance
you ran
distance then I'll add km for kilometers
print
the price is
I'm going to add a dollar sign
then our placeholder with price
and that should be good
your GPA is 3.2 you ran 2.5 kilometers
the price is 10.99 so those are floats
they're numbers that contain a decimal
portion even if the decimal had point
zero it would still be considered a
float whereas this would be an integer
so those are floats I'm going to turn
these lines into comments then we can
move on now we have strings a string is
just a series of text for example maybe
a username name equals type in your
first name it's just a series of
characters those are strings how about
food what's your favorite food I like
pizza
I'll add that to my variable food then
what about an email email equals make up
some email
bro123 gmail.com
now with strings they can contain
numbers but we treat them differently
than integers and floats integers and
floats we can use with arithmetic
equations here they're more or less just
characters so a string is just a series
of characters within quotes these can be
single quotes or double quotes then
let's display these for practice
let's say
hello
our variable name
you like our variable food
your email
is
our email variable hello bro you like
pizza your email is bro123 gmail.com so
those are strings it's a series of text
okay then lastly we have booleans a
Boolean is either true or false it's
binary it's kind of like a light switch
a Boolean variable can have only one of
two states true or false typically
booleans are used internally within a
program for example maybe we have a
Boolean variable named online if
somebody is online this can be set to
true if they're offline it could be
false let's set that to true
what if something is for sale four sale
if it's available we could say true if
not it's false it only has two states
then what about running is some process
running running equals true or false
then let's print these
print
what could we say with online
are you online
then let's print our variable online
print
is the
item for sale
for sale
perhaps running refers to a game is the
game running game running colon space
our running variable
so are you online true is the item for
sale false game running true typically
with booleans you use these internally
it's not common to print them directly
usually we would use these with if
statements
such as if then the Boolean if some
process is running print the game is
running
else
print
the game is over
I'm just going to turn these into
comments
so if running is true the game is
running if it's false
you would do something else the game is
over but I'll discuss this more when we
reach if statements you don't need to
know them at this point in time just
understand for now a Boolean is either
true or false oh here's another thing a
common mistake that people do with
booleans is that they may put them
within quotes
you can see that the color scheme
changed this is technically a string
it's within quotes so that's a common
mistake that people might make if you're
writing a Boolean make sure it's not
within quotes and the first letter is
capital
before I wrap things up I'm going to
show you a few tips and tricks with
variables suppose we have three
variables x equals one y equals two Z
equals three then I'll print these
variables directly print X
print why
print Z this would result in one two
three another possibility in place of
assigning these variables on separate
lines you could do so all on one line we
could write X comma y comma Z equals one
comma two comma three that would do the
same thing and it only takes one line of
code this is referred to as multiple
assignment if you ever need to set
multiple variables to the same value
this is what you could do I need to set
X Y and Z all to zero maybe they are
coordinates or something
what I would instead type is x equals y
equals z equals zero or some other value
so x y and z are all zero if I were to
change this number to one well they all
equal one that's how to set multiple
variables to the same value variable one
equals variable two equals however many
more variables you have all right
everybody those are variables a variable
is a reusable container for storing a
value a variable behaves as if it were
the value it contains we discussed four
data types integers which are whole
numbers
floats which are numbers that contain a
decimal portion
strings which are a series of text like
a name or an email and booleans which
are either true or false they're binary
so yeah that's an introduction to
variables in python in the comments
section why don't you post four
variables an integer a float a string
and a Boolean try and think of a unique
example that I didn't cover already so
yeah those are variables in Python